Inventory of the James Barron Hope Papers (I) 1790-1965
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers of James Barron Hope, 1835-1963, n.d. (Box 1-2)
  - Box 1, 1835-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-125)
    - [James Barron Hope], Richmond, to Annie, 31 May 1862. (Box-folder 1:89)
      "My court still continues...."; confidence in final victory; "today the city of Washington is in one universal shiver from Old Abe down...."; plan to cut off Washington and invade the North; Southern army set at 80 to 90,000 men, the Northern 115,000.
    - James Barron Hope, C. S. N., Richmond, Virginia, to his wife Annie, 10 June 1862. (Box-folder 1:90)
      Letter concerns his position as Judge Advocate of Court convened to consider the burning of vessels on Lake Ponchartrain, Louisiana.
    - G. M. Hollins, Flag Officer, C. S. N, Richmond, to James Barron Hope, Richmond, 25 June 1862. (Box-folder 1:91)
      Appointment as Secretary to the Naval Board for the examination of Midshipmen.
    - G. M. Hollins to James Barron Hope, 18 July 1862. (Box-folder 1:91)
      Order to report to Savannah.
    - G. M. Hollins to James Barron Hope, 18 July 1862. (Box-folder 1:91)
      Granted leave of Absence.
    - Recommendation of Jas. Barron Hope for the position of Quartermaster signed by J. Lyons, J. P. Holcombe, M. R. H. Garnett, C. F. Collins, 9 October 1862. (Box-folder 1:92)
      Recommendation included with following letter of 11 October 1862, Box-folder 1:92.
    - James Lyons, Ho[use] of Repres[entatives], to Genl. A. C. Myer, 11 October 1862. (Box-folder 1:92)
      Letter covering above recommendation of 9 October 1862, Box-folder 1:92.
    - Drury Lacey, Warrenton, [North Carolina], to John W. Norwood, [Hillsboro, North Carolina], 4 November 1862. (Box-folder 1:93)
      Introducing James Barron Hope who is in Hillsboro to find a place for his family.
    - S[amuel] Barron, Flag Officer [C. S. N.], Richmond, to J[ames] Barron Hope, Warrenton, North Carolina, 7 November 1862. (Box-folder 1:94)
      Appointment as Secretary to the "Flag Officer" commanding the Naval Forces in the waters of Virginia.
    - S. Barron to James [Barron Hope],10 November 1862. (Box-folder 1:95)
      The Flag of S[amuel] Barron has been hoisted above the "Patrick Henry."
    - Commission of Capt. Jas. Barron Hope as "Assistant Quartermaster's Captain" in the Provisional Army of the Confederate States, 18 November 1862. (Box-folder 1:96)
      Signed G. W. Smith, Secretary of War.
    - E. A. Cleveland to J[ames] Barron Hope, Warrenton, North Carolina, 23 November 1862. (Box-folder 1:97)
      Letter concerns copies of Hope's poems.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife Annie, 8 January 1863. (Box-folder 1:98)
      News that Burnside's army is landing on the coast.
    - Receipt for bond for Capt. James Barron Hope as Asst. Quartermaster, signed R. G. H. Kean, Chief of Bureau of War, C. S. A., Richmond, Virginia, 16 January 1863., 2 copies. PADS. (Box-folder 1:99)
    - Assignment of James Barron Hope to duty, signed A. C. Myers, 19 January 1863. (Box-folder 1:100)
    - Request by James Barron Hope for quarters according to his rank and grade, 31 January 1863. (Box-folder 1:100)
    - J. E. Dalney, Pittsylvania C[our]t H[ou]se, to [James Barron Hope], 25 January 1863. (Box-folder 1:101)
      Letter concerns a place being found for his family; congratulations on position in the Capital. Endorsement to his wife Annie.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope], Richmond, to his wife Annie, 28 January 1863. (Box-folder 1:102)
      Letter concerns question whether mail has been stopped; family matters.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife, 8 February 1863. (Box-folder 1:103)
      Gait died of small pox; family matters.
    - Grant of leave of absence for Capt. J[ames] Barron Hope, A. Q. M. by A. C. Myers, 9 March 1863. (Box-folder 1:104)
    - S. R. Mallory, Secretary of the Navy, C. S. A. to Capt. James Barron Hope, A. Q. M., Richmond, 27 April 1863. (Box-folder 1:105)
      Permission to use Navy files.
    - Maj. W. W. Peirce to Capt. Saml. R. Chisman, A. Q. M., Greensboro, North Carolina, 25 May 1863. (Box-folder 1:106)
      Letter concerns purchase of Army supplies.
    - Saml. R. Chisman, Greensboro, North Carolina, to [James Barron] Hope,26 May 1863. (Box-folder 1:107)
      Letter concerns problems of the Quartermaster's Department of the Confederate Army. Letter is continued with the letter below of 11 June 1863, Box-folder 1:107.
    - 11 June 1863. S[amuel] R. C[hisman] to [James Barron] H[ope]. ads. (Box-folder 1:107)
      Continuation of the above letter of 26 May 1863, Box-folder 1:107.
    - John Tyler, Sherwood Forest, to Jas. Barron Hope,11 July 1863. (Box-folder 1:108)
      "What an absurd document we have in Lincoln's message--and how...disgusting the proceedings of Congress...."
    - W. Gordon McCabe, Charleston, to [James Barron] Hope,21 August 1863. (Box-folder 1:109)
      Letter concerns the effect of Yankee fire on Fort Sumter; of the fire of "Ironsides," "Monitor," etc.; Charleston will be lost if the second line of James Island is not held.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife, 8 August 1863. (Box-folder 1:110)
      " Genl. M[yers] has been superseded by Genl. Lawton, a victim of Mr. Davis personal animosity."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to Mrs. James Barron Hope, Pine Hall, Stokes County, North Carolina, [10 August 1863]. (Box-folder 1:111)
      While awaiting the new "chief"; bonds, his wife is to handle; impression of new General [Lawton].
    - [James Barron Hope] to Annie, 12 August 1863. (Box-folder 1:112)
      Bond coupons turned up; family matters.
    - J[ames] Barron Hope to Sam[uel] [Barron],13 August 1863. (Box-folder 1:113)
      Letter concerns fever that is spreading on Mr. A's plantation, where his family is staying-need to move them; Genl. L[awton] is from Georgia, a gentleman of intelligence, successor to Myers; an official letter that is " Very cheerful about Charleston."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife Annie, 23 [August] 1863., 6 pages. (No. 10). ads. (Box-folder 1:114)
      Letter concerns strike in the city Post Office, so letters should be sent in a packet by Express; fall of Sumter, better works lay behind; "new chief."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope],[Richmond], to his wife, 9 September 1863. (Box-folder 1:115)
      Letter concerns box from Bermuda with cotton, soap, etc.; cake sent from Richmond to his family. Result in Tennessee very grand, "son they think here"; Rosecranz in a difficult position-- "it will puzzle the Yankees to reinforce him."
    - Orders for Capt. James Barron Hope to report to Greensboro, North Carolina, to Maj. Chisman, 10 October 1863. (Box-folder 1:116)
      Signed by Jno. Withers, Asst. Adjutant General.
    - James [Barron Hope] to his mother, n.d. [1863]. (Box-folder 1:117)
      Letter concerns Christian faith.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope], Richmond, [to his wife], [1863]., 4 pages. Incomplete. ads. (Box-folder 1:118)
      Letter concerns high prices for clothes; family matters.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife Annie, [1863]. (Box-folder 1:119)
      Letter concerns a visit to the "Merrimac"; Burnside expedition and other news of battles.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife Annie, [1863]. (Box-folder 1:120)
      Letter concerns slight sickness and his old wound from his duel; the falling back of Southern forces shortens their lines, brings the enemy further from his base; hope that Belgian, French and English fleets will break the blockade of New Orleans.
    - [James Barron Hope to his wife], n.d. [1863]. (Box-folder 1:121)
      Mention of Sam [Barron, IV]; "Our army in North Carolina number 65,000 & we expect to beat the enemy whenever they advance, & Comm. Barron (11.1) told me that Mr. Randolph (late Secy [of the Army]) told him that Genl. Johnson telegraphed that the Murfreesboro fight was a splendid victory, after all."
    - Request for leave of absence due to health, by James Barron Hope, endorsed, 16 June 1864. (Box-folder 1:122)
    - Eug. E. McLean, Lt. Col., Richmond, to Capt. J[ames] Barron Hope, Greensboro, North Carolina, 16 June 1864. (Box-folder 1:123)
      Permission to go on leave on forwarding the Surgeon's Certificate. Reply of 20 July 1864 listed below.
    - H. L. Clay, Assistant Adjutant General, grants Capt. J[ames] Barron Hope a sixty day leave, 20 July 1864. (Box-folder 1:123)
      Permission for leave requested on 16 June 1864, list above.
    - Benj. S. Ewell, President, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, to Capt. James Barron Hope, 9 July 1866. (Box-folder 1:124)
      Sends a diploma by direction of the Faculty.
    - Master of Arts Degree from the College of William and Mary, granted to James Barron Hope, June 1866. (Box-folder 1:125)
      Signed by E. Taliaferro and Benj. S. Ewell, President.
  - Box 2, 1872-1907, n.d. (Box-folder 2:1-139)
    The activity of Hope after the war is reflected in the correspondence included in Box 2. A duel which was averted only by the arrest of his challenger, 1873, his resignation as Editor of the Norfolk Virginian to start his own paper, The Landmark and his appearance to read anniversary poems at the Yorktown Centennial are among the events which concern the correspondence. There is also much family correspondence, many letters including humorous sketches, doggerel, and full poems.
    - W. H. Taylor, Richmond, to Capt. [James Barron Hope], 24 January 1872. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Letter concerns a Bill which has passed the Senate, authorizing construction of the Norfolk & Southern Railway through Richmond.
    - M. F. Maury, Office of Physical Survey, VMI, Lexington, Virginia, to James Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 26 January 1872. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Letter concerns the interest of the French Government in the James River Canal.
    - James Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, to J. B. Walters, 28 March 1872. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Letter concerns arrangements for a duel which was to take place near South Mills, North Carolina. Endorsement by J[aney] H[ope] M[arr], 1929, states that Walters was arrested in Norfolk before the duel could be fought.
      Enclosures:
      (1) A list of terms of a duel on stationery of the Norfolk Virginian.
      (2) Receipt for the cleaning of a pair of pistols. ACop. E. Encl.
    - S[usan] V[irginia] [Barron] Pendergast, Philadelphia, to James [Barron Hope],1 April [1873]. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Letter states that she is dreadfully anxious (probably about the duel which is in the papers; a duel that was never fought).
    - W. H. F. Lee, White House, Fish Hail P.O., King William County, Virginia, to Col. J. Barron Hope,15 May 1873. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Giving information on the size and management of Gen. Washington's farms, 1792.
    - Jno. S. Lindsay, Warrenton, Virginia, to Jas. Barron Hope, Virginian office, 25 June 1873. (Box-folder 2:6)
      Appreciation for an ode by Hope read by Judge Smith.
    - Clucking [?], Washington, to James Barron Hope, 28 July 1873. (Box-folder 2:7)
      Letter concerns the annoyance of "Tom Kelly's dog."
    - Glennan and Adkisson, Norfolk, to Capt. James Barron Hope, 29 September 1873. (Box-folder 2:8)
      Regret that Hope has withdrawn as Editor of the Virginian.
    - "Presentation Address...on behalf of the Compositors of the Norfolk Virginian on the occassion of the retirement of James Barron Hope," 1 October 1873. (Box-folder 2:9)
    - W. H. F. Lee, King William County, to James Barron Hope, 24 November 1873., 2 pages. ads. (Box-folder 2:9a)
    - Janey [Hope] to "Papa" [James Barron Hope], 13 August 1874. (Box-folder 2:10)
      Endorsed by James Barron Hope. Letter concerns French reading and her sister Nannie.
    - "Papa" [James Barron Hope] at Alleghany Springs, to Janey [Hope],31 August 1874., 6 pages. ads. (Box-folder 2:11)
      Family affairs.
    - "Papa" [James Barron Hope] at Alleghany Springs, to "Mama," Janey, and Nan, 4 September 1874. (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Capt. Jas. Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 3 October 1874. (Box-folder 2:12)
      Appreciation and regret at his indisposition.
    - "Report of Nannie M. Hope for Half-Session," signed by Susan V. Bagnall, 2 July 1875. (Box-folder 2:13)
    - Paul H. Hayne, "Copse Hill," Augusta, Georgia, to [James Barron Hope], 8 July 1875. (Box-folder 2:14)
      Appreciation for the review of his book in The Landmark.
    - J. A. Early, Lynchburg, to Capt. Jas. Barron Hope,13 September 1875. (Box-folder 2:15)
      Letter concerns an address Early was to deliver at Liberty.
    - Hugh Blair Grigsby, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse], Virginia, to James Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 14 January 1876. (Box-folder 2:16)
      "...heartly concur with you in every effort to bring the power of the Federal Executive within proper limits...."
    - John W. Johnston, U.S. Senate, Washington, to [James Barron] Hope,24 March 1876. (Box-folder 2:17)
      Appreciation for "defence of Gen. Ransom against the malicious charge recently directed against him."
    - J[ames] B[arron] H[ope] to Miss Jennie Barron Hope, care of Commodore S. Barron ["Malvern"], Loretto P.O., Essex County, Virginia, 18 June 1876. (Box-folder 2:18)
      Letter discusses family matters and "my Williamsburg speech."
    - Hugh Blair Grigsby, "Smithfield," Charlotte County, Virginia, to Miss Janey Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 2 January 1879., 6 pages. ads. (Box-folder 2:19)
      Compliments on a story by her which appeared in The Landmark; value of poetry and Bible reading for an author.
    - T. H. Stevens, Washington, to [James Barron Hope], 4 January 1879. (Box-folder 2:20)
      Appreciation for the criticism of his verses.
    - Robt. C. Winthrop, Boston, to James Barron Hope, 24 May 1879. (Box-folder 2:21)
      Appreciation for pamphlets and kind article in The Landmark.
    - William F. Barry, Fort McHenry, Baltimore, to Capt. Jas. Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 24 June 1879. (Box-folder 2:22)
      Letter concerns the pistols used in the Barron-Decatur duel, supposed to be in the possession of Col. Elliott, son of Barron's second in the duel.
    - R. E. Withers, Wytheville, Virginia, to James Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 4 October 1879. (Box-folder 2:23)
      Letter concerns political affairs in Norfolk and Portsmouth.
    - Baker P. Lee, Richmond, to Jas. Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 24 October 1879. (Box-folder 2:24)
      Compliments on his speech at Yorktown.
    - Schele De Vere, University of Virginia, to James Barron Hope, 20 March 1880. (Box-folder 2:25)
      A discussion of possible changes from French words to make English (American) proper names.
    - "Papa" [James Barron Hope], Office of The Landmark, Norfolk, Virginia, to Mrs. James Barron Hope, care of M. Taliaferro, 19 August 1880. (Box-folder 2:26)
      "...deeply pained I am to leave you...on such a mission as now engaged me....I am obeying a sense of duty ...."
    - Request of the Board of Visitors and Governors of the College of William and Mary that James Barron Hope cooperate with the committee for the restoration of the College, in connection with the Yorktown celebration, 27 August 1880. (Box-folder 2:27)
    - Committee on Oration and Poem, Centennial Anniversary of surrender of Cornwallis at Yorktown, Washington, D.C., to James Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia. Invitation to "pronounce a poem" at the celebration, 16 December 1880. (Box-folder 2:28)
    - Fred W. W. Holliday, Governor's Office, Richmond, Virginia, to Capt. J[ames] Barron Hope,21 January 1881. (Box-folder 2:29)
      Appointing Hope the poet for Yorktown.
    - W. E. Christian, City Engineer's Office, Richmond, Virginia, to [James Barron] Hope,24 January 1881. (Box-folder 2:30)
      Requesting a letter of recommendation for Col. Jno. M. Brooke for the Presidency of Blacksburg College.
    - Robert C. Winthrop, Brookline, Massachusetts, to James Barron Hope, 20 May 1881., 4 pages. ads. (Box-folder 2:30a)
    - Ro. A. Brock to Capt. James Barron Hope, 2 July 1881. (Box-folder 2:31)
      Note of appreciation.
    - Certificate of the election of Capt. James Barron Hope to the Virginia Historical Society, 2 July 1881. (Box-folder 2:32)
    - Invitation to James Barron Hope to be present at the Yorktown Centennial, 18-21 October 1881, 19 September 1881., 5 admission cards. ads. (Box-folder 2:33)
      Invitation to Miss Janie Hope to same.
    - Mrs. S. Goode, Bernyville, to Janie [Hope],28 September 1881. (Box-folder 2:34)
      Offer to chaperone at Yorktown Celebration.
    - Printed invitation to the Yorktown Celebration. Printed Yorktown Celebration ribbon, 18 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:35)
    - Invitation to Capt. J. Barron Hope and Mrs. Hope from Major Gen'l. Hancock, the steamer "St. Johns," 19 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:36)
    - Invitation to the Misses Hope to the same, 19 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:37)
    - Description of the Yorktown Centennial by [Janey Barron Hope], 22 October 1881., 7 pages. ADr. E. (Box-folder 2:38)
    - Jno. S. Tucker, U.S. Senate, Washington, D.C., 25 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:39)
      Account of his reactions to the reading of his Yorktown Ode by James Barron Hope; comparing him to Homer.
    - Comments made by [Janey Barron Hope] at Norfolk, 25 October 1881., 7 pages. ADr. E. (Box-folder 2:40)
      Endorsement by A[nn] W. Marr, her daughter, in January 1961.
    - Jno S. Tucker, Secretary, Yorktown Centennial Celebration, Washington, D.C., to Capt. James Barron Hope, 31 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:41)
      Enclosing a copy of a resolution which is listed below, 25 October 1881, Box-folder 2:41.
    - Resolution of thanks for the "very eloquent and appropriate Centennial Poem delivered," signed by John W. Johnston, Chairman, 25 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:41)
      Enclosed within the above letter, 31 October 1881, Box-folder 2:41.
    - J. Stanley Brown, Private Secretary [Executive Mansion], Washington, D.C., to James Barron Hope (Mourning stationery), 29 October 1881. (Box-folder 2:42)
      Acknowledges, for the President, receipt of letter and "report of the verses."
    - Townsend Ward, Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, to Capt. J. Barron Hope,7 November 1881. (Box-folder 2:43)
      Request that Hope deliver his Yorktown ode in Philadelphia.
    - Robt. C. Winthrop, Brookline, Massachusetts, to Jas. Barron Hope,12 November 1881. (Box-folder 2:44)
      Appreciation of Yorktown poem and of allusions in it to himself.
    - Townsend Ward. Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, to Capt. James Barron Hope, 15 November 1881. (Box-folder 2:45)
      Enclosing an invitation to deliver his Yorktown ode in Philadelphia.
    - "Jeemes" [James Barron Hope], to Commodore S. Barron, Loretto P.O., Essex County, Virginia, 17 November 1881. (Box-folder 2:46)
      Letter concerns his invitation to recite his "Ode" before the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    - Fred. W. M. Holliday, Governor's Office, Richmond, Virginia, to Capt. J. Barron Hope,December 1881. (Box-folder 2:47)
      Letter concerns his last "Annual Message."
    - Fred. W. M. Holliday, Richmond, to Jas. Barron Hope,12 December 1881. (Box-folder 2:47)
    - Invitation to Mr. and Miss Hope from Miss Chew, Chiveden, 12 December [1881]., 6 cards. ads. C. (Box-folder 2:48)
      Includes one card for admission to the reading of "Yorktown Ode" by Capt. James Barron Hope.
    - Invitation to the delivery of Capt. James Barron Hope's "Yorktown Ode" at the Academy of Music, Philadelphia, 14 December 1881. (Box-folder 2:49)
    - 30 members of Congress, Washington, to Capt. James Barron Hope, 16 December 1881. (Box-folder 2:50)
      Request that the "eloquent Centennial Poem at Yorktown" be delivered in Washington.
    - Townsend Ward, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Captain Hope. 30 December 1881. (Box-folder 2:51)
      Notice of election as a member of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
      Enclosure contained within this letter listed below, Box-Folder 2:51.
    - Certificate of election of James Barron Hope to the Society, 30 December 1881. (Box-folder 2:51)
      Enclosure sent within above letter, Box-Folder 2:51.
    - Robt. C. Winthrop, Boston, to J[ames] Barron Hope,7 January 1882. (Box-folder 2:52)
      Massachusetts Historical Society is too small to bring Hope to Boston to read his Yorktown ode.
    - James Barron Hope, the Norfolk Landmark, Norfolk, Virginia, [to Col. J. M. Robinson], copied and forwarded by Geo. S. Rogers, 14 February 1882., 2 pages. ads. E. (Box-folder 2:53)
      States that he "cannot occupy any negative or doubtful attitude on any of the great questions now engaging public attention in this State."
    - "Papa" [James Barron Hope], the Norfolk Landmark, Norfolk, Virginia, to Janey [Hope],12 July 1882. (Box-folder 2:54)
      Letter concerns her writing; regards to her sister Nan.
    - [?], Bradford, England, to J[ames] Barron Hope,11 September 1882. (Box-folder 2:55)
      Letter concerns the reading of Hope's poem, "Charge at Balakiava" to audiences in England.
    - W. Talbot Walker and Theodore S. Garnett, Jr., Norfolk, to Capt. James Barron Hope, 10 October 1882. (Box-folder 2:56)
      Notice of election of President of the "St. Cecilia Society"; notice of his election as a Director of the Society.
    - J. A. Early, Alleghany Springs, to Capt. James Barron Hope, 26 August 1883. (Box-folder 2:57)
      Letter concerns the dowager Duchess of Sutherland who was a strong abolitionist and the young Duchess who was the reverse, in connection with an article. Endorsement by James Barron Hope.
    - "Papa" [James Barron Hope] to his daughters Janey and Nannie, 11 September 1883. (Box-folder 2:58)
      Letter concerns Mr. Marr who is at sea in a reported storm.
    - Invitation to J. Barron Hope to be a speaker at a "Virginia Victory" meeting, 9 November 1883. (Box-folder 2:59)
    - Wm. H. Parker to Janey [Barron Hope],4 December [1883]. (Box-folder 2:60)
      Glowing report on new book by Janey, "I hope you will not lay down your pen."
    - Edward S. Gregory, poem "To Miss Janey Barron Hope, in Salute to 'The Rescue'," 29 January 1884. (Box-folder 2:61)
    - Edward S. Joynes, South Carolina College, Columbia, South Carolina, to Hope, 29 January 1884. (Box-folder 2:62)
      Sends his congratulations after reading "The Rescue" by Miss Janey Barron Hope.
    - John Randolph Tucker, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to James Barron Hope, 9 February 1884. (Box-folder 2:63)
      Appreciation for kind words in The Landmark.
    - Wm. B. Taliaferro, Gloucester County, Virginia, to James Barron Hope, Norfolk, Virginia, 18 February 1884. (Box-folder 2:64)
      Appreciation for the receipt of a book by Janey [Hope], which "shows a careful study of the Colonial times."
    - William Couper, Florence, to Captain Hope, 23 March 1884. (Box-folder 2:65)
      Letter concerns his work as a portrait painter, and congratulations to Hope "on being the father of a rising young novelist."
    - E. L. Spottswood, M.D., Perrysville, Vermillion County, Indiana, to James Barron Hope, 28 May 1884. (Box-folder 2:66)
      Letter concerns his desire to obtain a copy of "The Rescue" in which his ancestor, Gov. Spottswood, figures.
      Enclosure contained within this letter listed below, Box-Folder 2:66.
    - Enclosure: John Tyler, Jr., to Dr. Spottswood. 28 May 1884. (Box-folder 2:66)
      Letter concerns that James Barron Hope could supply a copy of "The Rescue," by his daughter [Janey Hope].
      Enclosure sent within above letter, Box-Folder 2:66.
    - Announcing a fair and concert of the Pickett - Buchanan Camp Confederate Veterans, Norfolk, Virginia, 15 October 1884. (Box-folder 2:67)